# Iskren Ivanov

### Software Engineer

A communicative and enthusiastic developer who likes finding creative solutions to complicated problems of any scope. Passioned about product development, data management and UI/UX. With more than 5 years of commercial experience as a Front End & Full Stack Developer from mature large corporate projects to Greenfield and POC projects.



iskren.dev@gmail.com

Amsterdam, Netherlands

in linkedin.com/in/iskrenivanov

github.com/lsklvanov

+31 6 42494693

iskren.dev

twitter.com/dev\_iskren

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

ProgrammingJavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS (Technologies & React, Next.js, Storybook, Redux,LanguagesSCSS/Less ), Node.js, SQL, Java, PythonLibrariesRESTfull API, GraphQL, Context API,

Styled Components , Material UI, Bootstrap, GreenSock, Pixi, React Native

**Programming** Object Oriented Programming and **Testing** Unit Testing, Integration Tesing, E2E

**paradigms** Functional Programming Testing

Methodologies Agile, Scrum, Kanban, DevOps & CI/CD Tools Git, JIRA, Confluence, Bitbucket, GitHub,

Visual Studio Code, Web Storm, IntelliJ IDEA, Postman, DevTools, Bash, Docker,

AWS, Firebase

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Freelance Software Engineer - Frontend**Bol.com

11/2021 - 11/2022 Largest e-commerce platform in the Benelux region.

Achievements/Tasks

- Worked on implementing new features and functionality for the user interface, such as by adding support for new types of data or
  interactions, and integrating with external APIs and services to provide additional functionality in the most visited webshop in
  Benelux.
- Implemented all the required tests unit, integration and end to end tests for different parts of the system.
- Contributed and discussed code architecture and structure to improve overall readability, consistency and code scalability.
- Introduced new libraries and conducted demos to code owners on ways to implement them.
- Refactored older implementations and introduced new libraries to the codebase for better state menagment, data fetching and form handling eg. recoil, react query, zod, react-hook-form etc.
- Made small contributions on back end code and actively worked with back end engineers in defineing and developing APIs for accesing customer data from different micro services of bol.com.
- Worked in an Agile environment, resolved bugs and shipped features to production after every sprint. Conducted code reviews and pair programming sessions. Acted as a Scrum Master for a sprint.
- Build multiple pages and UX flows within bol.com account that resulted in more than 200k eu. company savings.
- Collaborating with designers and other stakeholders to ensure a consistent and user-friendly design across the application, and implementing design systems and component libraries to promote reuse-ability and consistency.
- Tech Stack: | Front End: React, TypeScript, Storybook, RTL, Design Systems. Back End: Java, Kotlin, Spring Boot. DevOps: Docker, Kubernetes, Gitlab CI | .

Contact: Carlien Nijland - cnijland@bol.com

Utrecht

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Front End Engineer - Contract

### Circularise

03/2021 - 11/2021 Netherlands

Circularise is a startup that brings transparency to global supply chains.

#### Achievements/Tasks

- Developed a dashboard to easily create, maintain and transact digital assets for supply chain traceability system.
- Built a POC that integrated web3.js to interact with Ethereum blockchain.
- Developed react application from the ground up and reused components.
- Integrated multiple libraries e.g. Okta, React Query, Formik to shorten implementation time and introduce new valuable features.
- Analyzed health, maintainability and scalability of external libraries and services e.g. licensing, contributors and community, to
  understand if it is a good fit for our project.
- Implementing client-side caching mechanisms to improve the performance of the application, such as by storing commonly used data
  and resources locally to reduce the need for network requests. Researched and discussed the implementation of a state menagment
  library.
- Led ongoing product discussions with Circularise stakeholders and team members to clarify both businesses, technical and UI/UX
  requirements in order to improve UI flows and implement new features.
- Working with the founder and other developers to identify and prioritize front-end development needs and requirements, and translating those needs into actionable plans and deliverables.
- Developed and implemented a strategy for continuous improvement and innovation for the front-end, such as by staying up-to-date with industry trends and best practices, and regularly incorporating new technologies and techniques into the codebase.
- *Tech Stack:* | *Front end*: React, TypeScript, Storybook, Next.js, Material UI, Tailwaind., Styled Components, React Query. *Back End*: Python, Fast API. *DevOps*: Docker, Gitlab CI |.

Contact: Kilian Marjew - kilian@circularise.com

# Front End Engeneer - Freelance

**Greener Power Solutions** 

12/2020 - 02/2021

Startup focused on delivering green energy from festivals to households.

Achievements/Tasks

- For this assignment I worked on a small MVP for Energy management system.
- Implemented a modern and scalable front-end architecture for the application.
- Integrated open-source libraries eg. Auth0, Formik, Graphana, GSAP and researched a few more to fit the use case of the EMS.
- Proposed, discussed and analysed front end solutions with Software Architect and CTO.
- Improving the overall codebase and architecture of the front-end system, such as by refactoring and modularizing code, and implementing automated testing and continuous integration systems to improve the reliability and maintainability of the application.
- Tech Stack: | Front End: React, TypeScript, Next.js, RTL, Material UI. Back End: Python, Fast API, DevOps: Docker, Gitlab CI|.

Contact: Jim van Oosten - jim@greener.nl

## **Front End Engineer - Freelance** StakeLogic

Game studio developing state of the art casino games.

Eindhoven, Netherlands

Amsterdam

Achievements/Tasks

05/2020 - 10/2020

- Contributed to the development of Stakelogic SDK.
- Developed new innovative (2D/3D) game features using Pixi.js (WebGL library) and TypeScript.
- Contributed to the development of desktop tool for improving games layout using Electron and TypeScript.
- Integrated React and developed global react components to achive more maintainable and scalable UI.
- Tech Stack: |TypeScript, Pixi.js, GSAP, Webpack, Node.js, Gulp, Jest|.

Contact: Emma Vereijken - emma@stakelogic.com

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Full Stack Engineer**

### Accenture

01/2019 - 05/2020 Fortune 500 company. Sofia, Bulgaria

### Achievements/Tasks

- Worked on multiple e-commerce projects for major corporate clients which all were recognized for meeting client expectations.
- Contributed to a large codebase with reliable and scalable code.
- Heavily contributed to e-commerce rebuild, migrating from jQuery to React and TypeScipt.
- Contributed to numerous back end services for a large e-commerce distributed application.
- Worked in an Agile environment with SCRUM teams located in multiple countries within EU.
- Delivered multiple features after every sprint and did demo to project stakeholders.
- Proficiently troubleshooted simple and complex technical issues of any scope for differently assigned projects, optimized speed and scalability over a variety of web aplications.
- Tech Stack: | Frontend: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, HTML/SCSS Backend: Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL |

# **Front End Engineer - Games**SkywindGroup Ltd.

04/2018 - 12/2018

Global entertainment technology solution provider.

Sofia, Bulgaria

#### Achievements/Tasks

- Implemented new features and mechanics that improve gameplay, and optimizing the performance of the game to ensure smooth and seamless experience for players.
- Collaborating with a team of designers, artists, and engineers to bring the game to life and deliver a high-quality experience for players.
- Consumed RESTful APIs and discussed endpoint improvements with back end engineers.
- Worked in an Agile environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.
- Fixed bugs and monitored games behaviour in different stages of the development while taking ownership for features before and after deployment.
- Made minor contributions to a game engine widely used in the development of SkywindGroup games.
- Tech Stack: |TypeScript, Pixi.js, GSAP, Webpack, Node.js, Gulp, Jest|.

# Web Developer

Dantek Ltd.

02/2017 - 04/2018 Creative marketing agency.

Sofia,Bulgaria

### Achievements/Tasks

- Developed and implemented custom websites and landing pages for the agency's clients, using modern web development technologies and frameworks.
- Worked with designers and other stakeholders to ensure that the agency's websites, landing pages are visually appealing, user-friendly, and optimized for search engines.
- Collaborating with other team members and stakeholders to develop and implement web-based marketing campaigns and initiatives, such as by implementing interactive content, landing pages, and email marketing campaigns.
- Tech Stack: | Html, SCSS, JavaScript, MJML, React, PHP |.

Contact: Dimitar Kirilov - dimitar.kirilov@lidango.com

# SOFT SKILLS

Adaptability Business Comunication Confident Creative Enthusiastic Flexible Goal Oriented

Imaginative Initiative Innovative Insightful Knowledgeable Proactive Problem Solving

Resourcefulness Teamwork Time Menagment

# **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

### CV Web App (11/2022 - 11/2022)

Small web app I'm currently building to showcase experince and interests. https://github.com/lsklvanov/CV/issues?q=is%3Aclosed

#### RSVP App

React Application for receiving responses from people interested in a particular event: https://github.com/lsklvanov/RSVPapp

### Score Board App

• Simple scoreboard application build with React: https://github.com/lsklvanov/ReactScoreBoardApp

### **LANGUAGES**

English Full Professional Proficiency Bulgarian

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Dutch

Elementary Proficiency

### **CERTIFICATES**

MTA: Software Development Fundamentals (06/2016 - 08/2016)

Certified Secure: Essential Security

Credential ID CSC-20220112-1287

# **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor's of Automation and Information Engineering** Technical University of Gabrovo

09/2012 - 06/2016

Thesis

 Web Application for Holiday Planning https://github.com/lsklvanov/Holiday\_planner 85% Overall Award Avarage

# **INTERESTS**

Chess

Snowboarding

Cycling

Travel

Weightlifting